[Music]
welcome to voice club and a platform for
transformative conversations this is a
voice club short taken from episode 12
on truth psychedelics and society the
message here although there's much much
more to unpack than what can possibly be
done in a video as short as this is
vitally important not only for the
project of voice club moving forward but
I think to a much grander level than
that close to the core of this message
is that you really best be aware of what
it is you don't understand about
yourself because what you don't
understand about yourself well it has
you for good or ill and so poised them
off the kind that young puts forward is
really not to be brushed aside this is
to say little more than where there's
potential there's danger and we do well
to keep both sides of the coin in mind
let's flip the coin here I'm going to
read out a passage that Cole Jung wrote
in a letter to Victor white and he wrote
this on the 10th of April 1954 is the
LSD drug you referring to mescaline it
has indeed very curious effects of which
I know far too little I don't know
either
what its psychotherapeutic value with
neurotic or psychotic Patience's I only
know there's no point in wishing to know
more of the collective unconscious than
one gets through dreams and intuition
the more you know of it the greater in
heavier becomes your moral burden
because the unconscious contents
transform themselves into your
individual tasks and duties as soon as
they become conscious do you want to
increase loneliness and misunderstanding
do you want to find more and more
complications and increasing
responsibilities you get enough of it
if I once could say that I had done
everything I know I had to do then
perhaps I should realize a legitimate
need to take mescaline if I should take
it now I would not be at all sure that I
had not taken it out of idle curiosity I
should hate the thought that I had
touched on the sphere where the paint is
made that colours the world where the
light is created that makes shine the
splendor of the dawn the lines and
shapes of
all form the sound that feels the orbit
the thought that illuminates the
darkness of the void there are some
impoverished creatures perhaps for whom
mescaline would be a heaven-sent gift
without a counter poison but I am
profoundly mistrustful of the pure gifts
of the gods you pay very dearly for them
this is not the point at all to know of
or about the unconscious nor does the
story end here on the contrary it is how
and where you begin the real quest if
you are too unconscious it is a great
relief to know a bit of the collective
unconscious but it soon becomes
dangerous to know more because one does
not learn at the same time how to
balance it through a conscious
equivalent that is the mistake Aldous
Huxley makes he does not know that he is
in the role of zelbel erring Sorcerer's
Apprentice who learned from his master
how to call the ghosts but did not know
how to get rid of them again
yeah so the reason that couple
paragraphs there came to mind I think
what young is getting at there is
perhaps it cuts very close to the core
of what the element of responsibility
that's incumbent on anyone who decides
they want to take a psychedelic
substance has to come to terms with you
know we've been talking about the fact
that these are if nothing else strange
and powerful things where strange here
is the very essence of strange and
powerful is at least on the
psychological and perhaps spiritual
level the very essence of power and the
question then becomes if you have such
experiences you can't quite put into
words but feel somehow filled with a
sense of meaning to take or integrate
some of that experience into a life well
how do you go about doing that
what should you orient towards what kind
of life facilitates the integration of
some of these experiences now young of
course references here that the
collective unconscious and it's a vast
domain of study filled with the
requirement to have a real deep relation
to a kind of psychological symbolism and
an appreciation of thematic content that
I think cuts at this area of confusion
about truth and where something like the
mystical parts of our world might meet
the scientific endeavor and there's
these strange things that are brought
together that pop up through and from a
place that we can construe as the
unconscious we could construe it as the
potential for human experience but that
they pop up in our experience and they
have the power in fact to orient our
action but also reveal how it is we are
already acting how we might be relating
to our parents or
friends in a particular social
environment how that might relate to
certain systems that are mechanically
involved in the cycle of the world
affairs
there can be an awareness of the of the
the power associated with what something
like a pure malevolent feeling is when
it's attached to someone who's animated
by a particular view of the world or a
particular ideology even though that
that person themself might think that
there might be the most benign person
maybe they are speaking purely
rationally and purely factually but in
actual fact it's it's somehow there's a
possession there thank you for listening
you can find the full conversation in
the description below if you're
interested in content like this do hit
the subscribe button and subscribe where
you usually listen to your podcasts can
also visit Voice club comm to join the
mailing list and there'll be a link to
patreon as well if you'd like to support
this project in a more committed way
voice club is a platform for
transformative conversations and there's
a lot more to come the next conversation
to be uploaded has been recorded in full
video as well as was the first episode
and it's a very interesting conversation
with a wonderfully interesting man his
name's Warren Roberts and he's an
entrepreneur who has provided people a
novel and important way to
reconceptualize our post-death rituals
in the Western world
you